[music]
Hi everyone, I'm Laise De Piantic and
I'm here today with Samuel introducing a
new part of the Pyantic stack. So let's
start with a little bit of context. So
tell me why did you decide to build
Pentic AI gateway?
>> Well, I guess there were there were two
two things that spurred me to to go and
do it. Um
one was that we we saw all this usage of
you know users using inference with
pantic AI but to to do that we were
building the the frameworks the way by
which they were interacting with LLMs.
But before they actually got to go and
use the library they had to go and sign
up for all of these different services.
Um and so we kind of wondered if we
could provide a service that would unify
uh the inference that was provided
without go without getting in the way
and breaking the functionality. And then
on the other side on the enterprise side
I spoke to a lot of companies who were
um building with AI and I heard two
solution two two answers only from them
and that was either we build our own
gateway it works but it's a pain to
maintain or we're using some of the
other um gateway options out there and
they're incredibly buggy. Um, and
there's a particular reason. I mean,
sure, everyone complains software is
buggy, but there was some very specific
reasons why lots of the existing kind of
prior art in the gateway space is so
unreliable. Um, which I'll get to in a
moment. But because of that, we decided
we would kind of have a crack at
building something that that that didn't
have those problems.
>> Okay. So basically then um the way I see
this is the two main advantages then to
to use the AI gateway then would be the
fact that you can switch through models
uh seamlessly um just with one line of
code and then also the fact that well
since you don't do translations then
does that mean that the moment that
things are released new models or new
formats are released you can use them on
penc gateway straight away is that it
>> yeah exactly so for example last week
Anthropic released their native support
for um structured outputs using um
custom grammarss. We didn't have to do
any work. That just worked out the box
on the day because it um it like we're
not doing anything to the request. We're
just doing the orth and the token
counting. Similarly, Gemini 3 came out
yesterday. On that occasion, we had to
go and add support if you wanted to use
our built-in um providers where you're
buying the inference uh through us. Um
we had to go and add price support for
um Gemini 3 which took a few minutes and
then you could then it would work and it
would have worked on bring your own key
immediately because again we're not
doing anything fancy with the the
request body. All we have to do is
um uh know how to uh intercept the
authentication and insert the the
upstream authentication and uh how to
intercept the usage and extract the
token counts to to calculate the price.
>> Uh but I know that there are a few more
key benefits to using puentia gateway.
Do you want to tell me about
>> So I think the first thing to say is
that we support two models of of buying
inference. You can either buy the
inference uh through us. So you
basically put your card in to the
gateway and then you can buy inference
from uh OpenAI, Anthropic, Google or
Amazon Bedrock or or Grock with a Q. Um
and we'll add more more soon. Um or you
can go and put your own key in and and
basically your own API key in and then
gateway is currently free. Um and we're
just doing the we will use that key for
the upstream. So you need to go and buy
that inference, but we'll intercept and
do the authentication so you can create
one API key that can connect to many
different um different LLMs and and
measure cost. And I think cost is the
the single biggest um differentiator.
You can set a budget um on a project
level, on a user level, or even on an
individual key level. And then you can
set budgeting on a month, week or day um
interval or or for keys you can set a
complete limit. So you can say this key
has $10 behind it forever and then you
could perhaps go and share that key with
someone doing it doing a trial or
something and know that they were going
to they can only ever spend um those
$10. On the enterprise side,
observability is one of the the big ads.
So you can drop your um pilantic logfire
write token into the gateway and now
every request that goes through it will
be recorded to the gate to to logfire.
Um uh that's a that's a big deal for
some enterprises where they don't want
um requ untrusted requests being made to
to LLMs. Um
and there's a whole bunch of other
features that are going to come come
soon. So in terms of uh caching of
requests which is super valuable in
situations like evals. So we already
have model fallback. Sorry I meant
forgot to mention that. So if one of the
models goes down. So Anthropic is a good
example where we support it through
three different providers. Anthropic um
Google and Bedrock. If one of them goes
down for some reason as for example
Anthropic did yesterday with a
Cloudflare outage uh we would fall back
to to Google and then to um Bedrock. Now
let's talk a little bit about open
source because that's the backbone of
Pyantic, right? So how is the Pentic AI
gateway with open source?
>> Yes. So so the the core of the gateway
is open source under AGPL3.
So we're not for the first time as a
company, we're not releasing something
under MIT and and I think we we think
it's really important that the core is
open source. We'll allow providers to
come along and implement their own orth
for for let's say a new model or sorry a
new provider wants to wants to be added
to the gateway. can do that work. It
also allows you as an end user to go and
see how it's how it's working. You can
even host the gateway yourself um
locally if you or run it locally or run
it um on on Cloudflare on your own
account. You'll just need to go and fill
in a TypeScript file to to set the
config effectively. So what you what is
closed source and what is purely
commercial is the the UI um for uh
administering it which uh I'll show you
in a minute in a in a demo.
>> If I'm enterprise and I'm really looking
for a new AI gateway solution, can I use
Pentic AI gateway?
>> Yeah, absolutely. So we offer offer um
service in three ways. So you can use
obviously our cloud um you can uh
self-host it on Cloudflare which is how
we deploy it. That's probably the
simplest option. You basically will give
you the the the files and the the code
to run it on your own own Cloudflare.
The only thing it needs beyond
Cloudflare is Postgress and then if you
don't want to run on Cloudflare, we also
offer it as a Docker container uh and a
Helm chart so that you can run it within
your own infra if that's what you want
to do.
>> Can you tell me a little bit more about
Cloudflare Edge and how Parenta Gateway
doesn't add uh latency to requests
because of the way that it was um
designed? Yeah. So I think the more
people use the the gateway day in day
out um the more important latency is. If
you are sitting in Australia let's say
and you want to connect to an LLM
provider uh elsewhere in Asia or also in
Australia, you really don't want every
one of your requests being rooted
through um some data center on the east
coast of the US. And so we've set up
gateway to run at the edge. So um on
Cloudflare's network of 200 300 data
centers so you're guaranteed to have a
data center near you in the same
generally in the same country or in the
same geographic region. And so you're
able to connect to your local or
relatively local LLM through a node
that's local. And the first request will
have to call back to the to the database
to get um information about the
providers for on an API key basis, but
beyond that, it's cached at the edge. So
the network request goes directly into
Cloudflare and then to the uh LLM
provider. As we as we've seen recently
with the um with the outage that we had
with Cloudflare, the very rare outage
that we saw with Cloudflare yesterday,
most of the big LM providers are
actually using Cloudflare themselves.
And so from after it's been terminated
in our gateway, it'll go through
Cloudflare's internal network um to the
LLM provider and then ultimately to
their inference. Um so it should add
singledigit milliseconds um of latency
up to 20 milliseconds of latency in the
in the common case.
Last question before we go for our demo
is I understand Pyantic now has a
collection of tools, right? Would you
explain to me how those tools actually
fit on a software development life
cycle?
>> Yeah, absolutely. So, we think of the
Pantic stack, our our suite of tools as
um as a way for developers to build with
AI in the best possible way. So anyone
who has gone beyond a demo knows that
although it might be easy to get to a
very compelling first day demo of look
how good AI is, it's quite a different
thing to to take that through and put
that into production and make it usable
by end users. And so the pilantic stack
starts with the original library pantic
validation. Then we have pyantic AI our
agent framework which we we talked a bit
about earlier. Then we have Pyantic
logfire um the observability platform
for understanding what the hell this
model and the rest of your application
are doing. And then lastly the newest
member of the of the team as it were is
Pantic AI gateway. Um and I think you
know pad gateway even more than the
others we we see a boring but necessary
task that we that developers need a
solution to that we can where we can go
and help and so so that's why we kind of
added it to the set and obviously they
all work well together pantic validation
and AI are completely open source and
then logfire and the gateway have open
source components but are also
commercial
>> and generous free tier on logfire
>> I think it's um I think it's worth
saying um the gateway while it's in beta
is effectively free as in we we don't
charge you for bring your own key and we
we charge you zero above the the cost of
the inference um from the LLM model
providers. We even eat the card fee at
the moment. So if you if it would have
cost you $10 on on OpenAI let's say it
should cost you $10 with us as well. Um
in time we will come up with a pricing
model where we make some money. We
obviously are a company but for now
while it's in beta it's completely free.
It's a really good opportunity to test
it out. Bring your keys and have some
fun with it. Um, see how the failover
and the change between models actually
work. Do some experimentation. Um,
wonderful. So, I think now it's time for
a demo.
>> Let me share my screen. Um, go to the
gateway.
I will log in. We have login by default
with Google and GitHub. If you're
enterprise, you can set up OIDC
providers today, which should work. And
you have a custom custom URL to log in.
I'll log in with my account. Here I can
see um uh data about the the usage uh of
this organization, the keys that are set
up. I can go and look at what providers
I have configured. So you see I have the
built-in providers and one non-bilt-in
provider. At the moment, these built-in
providers basically become available
when I have when I have a card in. and
they're the way that I can um
uh basically buy the inference through
us rather than putting in my own key,
but I could also add my own provider
with my own API key. Um but to actually
do some inference, I'm going to come
over here and I'm going to switch to
user mode. So this is the view that you
would see. All admins can see this, but
also if I was if I was um signed in just
as a user, I would see this simplified
view where it's just my API keys and uh
my spend. I don't have any budgets set
up for me, but if I in fact, let me let
me do that now. I can set um spending
limits for those keys. So, let me set a
$5 um $5 a day, uh $10 a week, uh $20 a
month limits. Uh and on a key, I can set
a total limit as well if I wanted to,
but I'll go and create that key. So, you
should now be able to see zed going to
copy paste that code snippet that it
gave me in the in the browser. And I'm
also going to copy the line to uh set
the API key. So that is copied directly
from from the gateway code. Um and with
[clears throat] that, that's all I
should need to go and um run this
example. The main thing to note is when
you're using the gateway within Pyanic
AI, the only thing you need to change to
to get gateway to work is to put
gateway/prefix on the front of your
existing model usage. So if you were
using anthropic um sonnet 45 in the
gateway in padant AI before all you need
to do to start using gateway is set that
API key and uh add gateway as a prefix
and I'll also print the result because
it's not much fun doing inference and
not saying what happened. Um and if I
now go and run that example
so we've we've successfully fully done
the inference through the gateway. And
if I want to use if I don't want to use
cloud anymore, let's say I'm curious now
about how I don't know Google vertex or
any other model is going to
>> let me let me try it with openAI 4.1 and
yes. So so through the same key I've
changed nothing other than the code and
you see immediately that works. Go on
then I'll try uh and use the Gemini
provider
uh Gemini
success. Um, and I'm just I might just
show you one other thing, which is how
that looks in in Logfire. Um, and I'm
gonna I just want to connect up the
gateway to Logfire. So, I'm going to
come back over as an admin. I'll come to
my projects, open my default project.
I'm going to click edit, and I'm going
to want to put in a logfire right token
here. I'm going to come into padantic
logfire settings. I'll generate a right
token here.
Give that a name. copy this token and we
will make this process even easier in
future but it's actually only the
process of copying one value.
Um, so we've now now set that. Um, so we
come back over to logfire, go to live
view and offscreen. I'll go and run that
Gemini example one more time
and again if the gods of demos are with
us. Yeah, you see immediately that
request come through and I can see the
exchange with the LLM, see the cost
incurred. Um, only one request here but
uh, gone. I'll I'll change it back to
OpenAI and do one more just to make the
point and so you can see yeah again
similar conversation input and output in
this case. There we are.
>> Perfect. Well, I think that's it.
>> We're going to have lots more features
to come. I think we sent out an email
yesterday to our existing users. We've
had an amazing reception since the
gateway launched. So, we have uh a bunch
of people on the platform already. We've
emailed them asking them what features
they want next. And this is obviously
early and in active development. So
follow us on socials to see what comes
next.
>> Absolutely. Also, um, paid.dev/gateway,
we'll get you to our website. You can
book a call. You can investigate what
we're up to if you join our Slack as
well. And yeah, loads of fun stuff
coming down the pipeline.
>> Thanks a lot.
>> Thank you. Bye-bye.